{
  "language": "Spanish",
  "flashcards": [
    {
      "topic": "Marine Life",
      "cards": [
        {
          "tense": "present",
          "wordcount": 1,
          "phrases": [
            { "front": "Fish", "back": "pez" },
            { "front": "Shrimp", "back": "camarón" },
            { "front": "Crab", "back": "cangrejo" },
            { "front": "Octopus", "back": "pulpo" },
            { "front": "Seaweed", "back": "alga" },
            { "front": "Starfish", "back": "estrella de mar" },
            { "front": "Jellyfish", "back": "medusa" },
            { "front": "Dolphin", "back": "delfín" },
            { "front": "Shark", "back": "tiburón" },
            { "front": "Seal", "back": "sello" },
            { "front": "Whale", "back": "ballena" },
            { "front": "Coral", "back": "coral" },
            { "front": "Clam", "back": "almeja" },
            { "front": "Lobster", "back": "langosta" },
            { "front": "Squid", "back": "calamar" },
            { "front": "Turtle", "back": "tortuga" },
            { "front": "Eel", "back": "anguila" },
            { "front": "Barnacle", "back": "percebe" },
            { "front": "Manta", "back": "olvidar" },
            { "front": "Plankton", "back": "plancton" },
            { "front": "Urchin", "back": "pilluelo" },
            { "front": "Crayfish", "back": "cangrejo de río" },
            { "front": "Oyster", "back": "ostra" },
            { "front": "Sea snake", "back": "serpiente marina" },
            { "front": "Seahorse", "back": "caballito de mar" }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "present",
          "wordcount": 2,
          "phrases": [
            { "front": "Big fish", "back": "pez grande" },
            { "front": "Fresh shrimp", "back": "camarones frescos" },
            { "front": "Red crab", "back": "cangrejo rojo" },
            { "front": "Smart octopus", "back": "pulpo inteligente" },
            { "front": "Green seaweed", "back": "algas verdes" },
            { "front": "Bright starfish", "back": "estrella de mar brillante" },
            { "front": "Soft jellyfish", "back": "medusas blandas" },
            { "front": "Fast dolphin", "back": "delfín rápido" },
            { "front": "Strong shark", "back": "tiburón fuerte" },
            { "front": "Playful seal", "back": "foca juguetona" },
            { "front": "Large whale", "back": "ballena grande" },
            { "front": "Colorful coral", "back": "coral colorido" },
            { "front": "Hard clam", "back": "almeja dura" },
            { "front": "Tasty lobster", "back": "langosta sabrosa" },
            { "front": "Small squid", "back": "calamar pequeño" },
            { "front": "Slow turtle", "back": "tortuga lenta" },
            { "front": "Long eel", "back": "anguila larga" },
            { "front": "Tiny barnacle", "back": "pequeño percebe" },
            { "front": "Graceful manta", "back": "olvido elegante" },
            { "front": "Floating plankton", "back": "plancton flotante" },
            { "front": "Spiky urchin", "back": "erizo puntiagudo" },
            { "front": "Fresh crayfish", "back": "cangrejos de río frescos" },
            { "front": "Salty oyster", "back": "ostra salada" },
            {
              "front": "Venomous sea snake",
              "back": "serpiente marina venenosa"
            },
            { "front": "Tiny seahorse", "back": "pequeño caballito de mar" }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "present",
          "wordcount": 3,
          "phrases": [
            { "front": "The fish swims", "back": "el pez nada" },
            {
              "front": "Fresh shrimp cooks",
              "back": "camarones frescos cocinados"
            },
            { "front": "Red crab hides", "back": "pieles de cangrejo rojo" },
            {
              "front": "Smart octopus moves",
              "back": "movimientos inteligentes del pulpo"
            },
            { "front": "Green seaweed grows", "back": "crecen algas verdes" },
            {
              "front": "Bright starfish shines",
              "back": "la estrella de mar brillante brilla"
            },
            {
              "front": "Soft jellyfish drifts",
              "back": "medusas suaves a la deriva"
            },
            {
              "front": "Fast dolphin jumps",
              "back": "saltos rápidos de delfines"
            },
            {
              "front": "Strong shark hunts",
              "back": "fuertes cacerías de tiburones"
            },
            { "front": "Playful seal swims", "back": "foca juguetona nadando" },
            { "front": "Large whale sings", "back": "gran ballena canta" },
            {
              "front": "Colorful coral grows",
              "back": "el coral colorido crece"
            },
            { "front": "Hard clam closes", "back": "la almeja dura se cierra" },
            {
              "front": "Tasty lobster steams",
              "back": "deliciosa langosta al vapor"
            },
            {
              "front": "Small squid hides",
              "back": "pieles de calamar pequeño"
            },
            {
              "front": "Slow turtle swims",
              "back": "la tortuga nada lentamente"
            },
            {
              "front": "Long eel slithers",
              "back": "el barco anguila se desliza"
            },
            {
              "front": "Tiny barnacle clings",
              "back": "pequeños percebes se aferran"
            },
            {
              "front": "Graceful manta swims",
              "back": "mantarraya nada con gracia"
            },
            {
              "front": "Floating plankton drifts",
              "back": "derivas de plancton flotante"
            },
            {
              "front": "Spiky urchin moves",
              "back": "el erizo puntiagudo se mueve"
            },
            {
              "front": "Fresh crayfish boils",
              "back": "cangrejos de río frescos hervidos"
            },
            {
              "front": "Salty oyster opens",
              "back": "la ostra salada se abre"
            },
            {
              "front": "Venomous sea snake slithers",
              "back": "serpiente marina venenosa se desliza"
            },
            {
              "front": "Tiny seahorse floats",
              "back": "pequeños caballitos de mar flotan"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "present",
          "wordcount": 4,
          "phrases": [
            { "front": "I see big fish", "back": "veo peces grandes" },
            {
              "front": "He catches fresh shrimp",
              "back": "él atrapa camarones frescos"
            },
            { "front": "They cook red crab", "back": "cocinan cangrejo rojo" },
            {
              "front": "She admires smart octopus",
              "back": "ella admira al pulpo inteligente"
            },
            {
              "front": "We collect green seaweed",
              "back": "recogemos algas verdes"
            },
            {
              "front": "He finds bright starfish",
              "back": "encuentra estrellas de mar brillantes"
            },
            {
              "front": "They touch soft jellyfish",
              "back": "tocan medusas suaves"
            },
            { "front": "I watch fast dolphin", "back": "veo delfines rápidos" },
            {
              "front": "She photographs strong shark",
              "back": "ella fotografía un tiburón fuerte"
            },
            {
              "front": "We observe playful seals",
              "back": "observamos focas juguetonas"
            },
            {
              "front": "He listens to whale",
              "back": "él escucha a la ballena"
            },
            {
              "front": "They admire colorful coral",
              "back": "admiran los corales coloridos"
            },
            { "front": "I open hard clam", "back": "abro una almeja dura" },
            {
              "front": "She cooks tasty lobster",
              "back": "ella cocina una langosta sabrosa"
            },
            {
              "front": "He prepares small squid",
              "back": "prepara calamares pequeños"
            },
            {
              "front": "We watch slow turtle",
              "back": "observamos tortuga lenta"
            },
            { "front": "I spot long eel", "back": "veo una anguila larga" },
            {
              "front": "She removes tiny barnacles",
              "back": "ella quita pequeños percebes"
            },
            { "front": "They swim with manta", "back": "nadan con mantas" },
            {
              "front": "I study floating plankton",
              "back": "estudio el plancton flotante"
            },
            {
              "front": "He avoids spiky urchins",
              "back": "evita a los erizos puntiagudos"
            },
            {
              "front": "We catch fresh crayfish",
              "back": "cogemos cangrejos de río frescos"
            },
            {
              "front": "She shucks salty oyster",
              "back": "ella descascara ostras saladas"
            },
            {
              "front": "He observes venomous snake",
              "back": "observa serpiente venenosa"
            },
            {
              "front": "They feed tiny seahorses",
              "back": "alimentan a pequeños caballitos de mar"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "present",
          "wordcount": 5,
          "phrases": [
            { "front": "I see a big fish", "back": "veo un pez grande" },
            {
              "front": "He catches fresh shrimp daily",
              "back": "él pesca camarones frescos diariamente"
            },
            {
              "front": "They cook red crab tonight",
              "back": "cocinan cangrejo rojo esta noche"
            },
            {
              "front": "She admires a smart octopus",
              "back": "ella admira a un pulpo inteligente"
            },
            {
              "front": "We collect green seaweed often",
              "back": "a menudo recolectamos algas verdes."
            },
            {
              "front": "He finds bright starfish easily",
              "back": "encuentra estrellas de mar brillantes fácilmente"
            },
            {
              "front": "They touch soft jellyfish carefully",
              "back": "tocan con cuidado las medusas blandas"
            },
            {
              "front": "I watch a fast dolphin",
              "back": "observo un delfín rápido"
            },
            {
              "front": "She photographs a strong shark",
              "back": "ella fotografía un tiburón fuerte"
            },
            {
              "front": "We observe playful seals swimming",
              "back": "observamos focas juguetonas nadando"
            },
            {
              "front": "He listens to a large whale",
              "back": "él escucha a una gran ballena"
            },
            {
              "front": "They admire colorful coral reefs",
              "back": "admiran los coloridos arrecifes de coral."
            },
            { "front": "I open a hard clam", "back": "abro una almeja dura" },
            {
              "front": "She cooks a tasty lobster",
              "back": "ella cocina una langosta sabrosa"
            },
            {
              "front": "He prepares small squid for dinner",
              "back": "él prepara pequeños calamares para la cena."
            },
            {
              "front": "We watch a slow turtle",
              "back": "observamos una tortuga lenta"
            },
            { "front": "I spot a long eel", "back": "veo una anguila larga" },
            {
              "front": "She removes tiny barnacles carefully",
              "back": "ella quita con cuidado los pequeños percebes."
            },
            {
              "front": "They swim with graceful manta",
              "back": "nadan con elegantes mantarrayas."
            },
            {
              "front": "I study floating plankton closely",
              "back": "estudio de cerca el plancton flotante."
            },
            {
              "front": "He avoids spiky sea urchins",
              "back": "evita los erizos de mar puntiagudos"
            },
            {
              "front": "We catch fresh crayfish together",
              "back": "juntos pescamos cangrejos de río frescos"
            },
            {
              "front": "She shucks a salty oyster",
              "back": "ella descascara una ostra salada"
            },
            {
              "front": "He observes a venomous sea snake",
              "back": "observa una serpiente marina venenosa"
            },
            {
              "front": "They feed tiny seahorses carefully",
              "back": "alimentan con cuidado a los pequeños caballitos de mar."
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "present",
          "wordcount": 6,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "I am watching a big fish",
              "back": "estoy viendo un pez grande"
            },
            {
              "front": "He catches fresh shrimp every day",
              "back": "él pesca camarones frescos todos los días."
            },
            {
              "front": "They are cooking red crab tonight",
              "back": "están cocinando cangrejo rojo esta noche"
            },
            {
              "front": "She admires the smart octopus swimming",
              "back": "ella admira al inteligente pulpo nadando"
            },
            {
              "front": "We collect green seaweed for lunch",
              "back": "recogemos algas verdes para el almuerzo."
            },
            {
              "front": "He finds bright starfish on beach",
              "back": "encuentra estrellas de mar brillantes en la playa."
            },
            {
              "front": "They touch soft jellyfish with care",
              "back": "tocan las medusas suaves con cuidado"
            },
            {
              "front": "I watch the fast dolphin jump",
              "back": "observo el rápido salto del delfín."
            },
            {
              "front": "She photographs the strong shark underwater",
              "back": "ella fotografía al fuerte tiburón bajo el agua."
            },
            {
              "front": "We observe playful seals in water",
              "back": "observamos focas juguetonas en el agua."
            },
            {
              "front": "He listens to the large whale",
              "back": "él escucha a la gran ballena"
            },
            {
              "front": "They admire colorful coral in ocean",
              "back": "admiran los coloridos corales en el océano."
            },
            {
              "front": "I open the hard clam slowly",
              "back": "abro la almeja dura lentamente"
            },
            {
              "front": "She cooks a tasty lobster tonight",
              "back": "ella cocina una sabrosa langosta esta noche."
            },
            {
              "front": "He prepares small squid for dinner",
              "back": "él prepara pequeños calamares para la cena."
            },
            {
              "front": "We watch a slow turtle swim",
              "back": "observamos una tortuga nadar lentamente"
            },
            {
              "front": "I spot the long eel swimming",
              "back": "veo la anguila larga nadando"
            },
            {
              "front": "She removes tiny barnacles from boat",
              "back": "ella saca pequeños percebes del barco"
            },
            {
              "front": "They swim with a graceful manta",
              "back": "nadan con una elegante manta"
            },
            {
              "front": "I study the floating plankton closely",
              "back": "estudio de cerca el plancton flotante."
            },
            {
              "front": "He avoids the spiky sea urchins",
              "back": "evita los erizos de mar puntiagudos"
            },
            {
              "front": "We catch fresh crayfish for dinner",
              "back": "cogemos cangrejos de río frescos para cenar"
            },
            {
              "front": "She shucks a salty oyster carefully",
              "back": "ella abre con cuidado una ostra salada"
            },
            {
              "front": "He observes a venomous sea snake",
              "back": "observa una serpiente marina venenosa"
            },
            {
              "front": "They feed the tiny seahorses carefully",
              "back": "alimentan con cuidado a los pequeños caballitos de mar."
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "past",
          "wordcount": 2,
          "phrases": [
            { "front": "Ate fish", "back": "comí pescado" },
            { "front": "Caught shrimp", "back": "camarones capturados" },
            { "front": "Saw crab", "back": "cangrejo sierra" },
            { "front": "Found octopus", "back": "pulpo encontrado" },
            { "front": "Collected seaweed", "back": "algas recolectadas" },
            { "front": "Saw starfish", "back": "vio estrellas de mar" },
            { "front": "Watched jellyfish", "back": "observó medusas" },
            { "front": "Spotted dolphin", "back": "delfín moteado" },
            { "front": "Observed shark", "back": "tiburón observado" },
            { "front": "Saw seal", "back": "sello de sierra" },
            { "front": "Heard whale", "back": "ballena escuchada" },
            { "front": "Touched coral", "back": "coral tocado" },
            { "front": "Ate clam", "back": "comí almejas" },
            { "front": "Cooked lobster", "back": "langosta cocida" },
            { "front": "Caught squid", "back": "calamares capturados" },
            { "front": "Saw turtle", "back": "tortuga sierra" },
            { "front": "Spotted eel", "back": "anguila moteada" },
            { "front": "Removed barnacle", "back": "percebe eliminado" },
            { "front": "Saw manta", "back": "manta sierra" },
            { "front": "Found plankton", "back": "se encontró plancton" },
            { "front": "Spotted urchin", "back": "erizo moteado" },
            {
              "front": "Caught crayfish",
              "back": "cangrejos de río capturados"
            },
            { "front": "Ate oyster", "back": "comí ostra" },
            { "front": "Saw sea snake", "back": "vio serpiente marina" },
            { "front": "Spotted seahorse", "back": "caballito de mar moteado" }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "past",
          "wordcount": 3,
          "phrases": [
            { "front": "I ate fish", "back": "comí pescado" },
            {
              "front": "He caught shrimp yesterday",
              "back": "ayer pescó camarones"
            },
            {
              "front": "They saw crab on shore",
              "back": "vieron cangrejos en la orilla"
            },
            {
              "front": "We found octopus in tidepool",
              "back": "encontramos pulpo en una poza de marea."
            },
            {
              "front": "She collected seaweed for salad",
              "back": "ella recogió algas para ensalada."
            },
            {
              "front": "I saw starfish at beach",
              "back": "vi estrellas de mar en la playa"
            },
            {
              "front": "He watched jellyfish float by",
              "back": "observó cómo pasaban las medusas flotando"
            },
            {
              "front": "They spotted dolphin swimming close",
              "back": "vieron delfines nadando cerca"
            },
            {
              "front": "We observed shark near boat",
              "back": "observamos un tiburón cerca del barco."
            },
            {
              "front": "She saw seal lounging on rock",
              "back": "ella vio una foca descansando sobre una roca."
            },
            {
              "front": "I heard whale songs underwater",
              "back": "escuché cantos de ballenas bajo el agua"
            },
            {
              "front": "They touched coral reefs carefully",
              "back": "tocaron los arrecifes de coral con cuidado"
            },
            {
              "front": "He ate clam chowder yesterday",
              "back": "comió sopa de almejas ayer"
            },
            {
              "front": "We cooked lobster for dinner",
              "back": "cocinamos langosta para la cena"
            },
            {
              "front": "She caught squid at night",
              "back": "ella pescó calamares por la noche"
            },
            {
              "front": "I saw turtle swimming gracefully",
              "back": "vi una tortuga nadando con gracia."
            },
            {
              "front": "He spotted eel hiding in rocks",
              "back": "vio una anguila escondida en las rocas"
            },
            {
              "front": "She removed barnacle from shell",
              "back": "ella sacó el percebe de la concha"
            },
            {
              "front": "They saw manta ray gliding",
              "back": "vieron una manta raya planeando"
            },
            {
              "front": "I found plankton in water",
              "back": "encontré plancton en el agua."
            },
            {
              "front": "He spotted urchin in tidepool",
              "back": "vio un erizo en una poza de marea"
            },
            {
              "front": "We caught crayfish in stream",
              "back": "cogimos cangrejos de río en el arroyo"
            },
            {
              "front": "She ate oyster on half-shell",
              "back": "ella comió ostra en media concha"
            },
            {
              "front": "He saw sea snake swim",
              "back": "vio nadar a una serpiente marina"
            },
            {
              "front": "They spotted seahorse in coral",
              "back": "vieron caballitos de mar en el coral"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "past",
          "wordcount": 4,
          "phrases": [
            { "front": "I caught a big fish", "back": "atrapé un pez grande" },
            {
              "front": "She cooked fresh shrimp yesterday",
              "back": "ella cocinó camarones frescos ayer"
            },
            {
              "front": "They saw a red crab",
              "back": "vieron un cangrejo rojo"
            },
            {
              "front": "He found an octopus hiding",
              "back": "encontró un pulpo escondido"
            },
            {
              "front": "We collected seaweed for lunch",
              "back": "recogimos algas para el almuerzo."
            },
            {
              "front": "I saw a bright starfish",
              "back": "vi una estrella de mar brillante"
            },
            {
              "front": "He watched a floating jellyfish",
              "back": "observó una medusa flotando"
            },
            {
              "front": "They spotted a fast dolphin",
              "back": "avistaron un delfín veloz"
            },
            {
              "front": "We observed a hungry shark",
              "back": "observamos un tiburón hambriento"
            },
            {
              "front": "She saw a playful seal",
              "back": "ella vio una foca juguetona"
            },
            {
              "front": "I heard a singing whale",
              "back": "escuché una ballena cantando"
            },
            {
              "front": "They touched a colorful coral",
              "back": "tocaron un coral colorido"
            },
            {
              "front": "He ate a delicious clam",
              "back": "comió una almeja deliciosa"
            },
            {
              "front": "We cooked a fresh lobster",
              "back": "cocinamos una langosta fresca"
            },
            {
              "front": "She caught a small squid",
              "back": "ella atrapó un calamar pequeño"
            },
            { "front": "I saw a slow turtle", "back": "vi una tortuga lenta" },
            {
              "front": "He spotted a long eel",
              "back": "vio una anguila larga"
            },
            {
              "front": "She removed a tiny barnacle",
              "back": "ella sacó un pequeño percebe"
            },
            {
              "front": "They saw a graceful manta",
              "back": "vieron una elegante manta"
            },
            {
              "front": "I found some floating plankton",
              "back": "encontré algo de plancton flotando."
            },
            {
              "front": "He spotted a spiky urchin",
              "back": "vio un erizo puntiagudo"
            },
            {
              "front": "We caught a big crayfish",
              "back": "cogimos un cangrejo de río grande"
            },
            {
              "front": "She ate a fresh oyster",
              "back": "ella comió una ostra fresca"
            },
            {
              "front": "He saw a venomous sea snake",
              "back": "vio una serpiente marina venenosa"
            },
            {
              "front": "They spotted a tiny seahorse",
              "back": "vieron un pequeño caballito de mar"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "past",
          "wordcount": 5,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "I ate fresh big fish",
              "back": "comí pescado grande y fresco"
            },
            {
              "front": "She cooked the sweet shrimp",
              "back": "ella cocinó los camarones dulces"
            },
            {
              "front": "They caught red crab yesterday",
              "back": "ayer pescaron cangrejo rojo"
            },
            {
              "front": "He found a smart octopus",
              "back": "encontró un pulpo inteligente"
            },
            {
              "front": "We collected green seaweed together",
              "back": "recogimos algas verdes juntos"
            },
            {
              "front": "I saw bright starfish today",
              "back": "hoy vi estrellas de mar brillantes"
            },
            {
              "front": "He watched soft jellyfish float",
              "back": "observó cómo flotaban medusas suaves"
            },
            {
              "front": "They spotted a fast dolphin",
              "back": "avistaron un delfín veloz"
            },
            {
              "front": "We observed a strong shark",
              "back": "observamos un tiburón fuerte"
            },
            {
              "front": "She saw playful seals swimming",
              "back": "ella vio focas juguetonas nadando"
            },
            {
              "front": "I heard the singing whale",
              "back": "escuché a la ballena cantando"
            },
            {
              "front": "They touched colorful coral reefs",
              "back": "tocaron coloridos arrecifes de coral"
            },
            {
              "front": "He ate a hard clam",
              "back": "se comió una almeja dura"
            },
            {
              "front": "We cooked a tasty lobster",
              "back": "cocinamos una langosta sabrosa"
            },
            {
              "front": "She caught a small squid",
              "back": "ella atrapó un calamar pequeño"
            },
            { "front": "I saw a slow turtle", "back": "vi una tortuga lenta" },
            {
              "front": "He spotted a long eel",
              "back": "vio una anguila larga"
            },
            {
              "front": "She removed tiny barnacles quickly",
              "back": "ella eliminó rápidamente pequeños percebes."
            },
            {
              "front": "They swam with a manta",
              "back": "nadaron con una manta"
            },
            {
              "front": "I studied floating plankton closely",
              "back": "estudié de cerca el plancton flotante."
            },
            {
              "front": "He avoided spiky sea urchins",
              "back": "evitaba los erizos de mar puntiagudos"
            },
            {
              "front": "We caught fresh crayfish today",
              "back": "hoy pescamos cangrejos de río frescos"
            },
            {
              "front": "She shucked a salty oyster",
              "back": "ella abrió una ostra salada"
            },
            {
              "front": "He observed a venomous sea snake",
              "back": "observó una serpiente marina venenosa"
            },
            {
              "front": "They fed tiny seahorses carefully",
              "back": "alimentaron cuidadosamente a los pequeños caballitos de mar."
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "past",
          "wordcount": 6,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "I ate the fresh big fish",
              "back": "comí el pescado grande y fresco"
            },
            {
              "front": "She cooked the sweet fresh shrimp",
              "back": "ella cocinó los camarones frescos y dulces."
            },
            {
              "front": "They caught a red crab yesterday",
              "back": "ayer atraparon un cangrejo rojo"
            },
            {
              "front": "He found a smart octopus hiding",
              "back": "encontró un pulpo inteligente escondido"
            },
            {
              "front": "We collected green seaweed for salad",
              "back": "recogimos algas verdes para ensalada."
            },
            {
              "front": "I saw the bright starfish today",
              "back": "hoy vi la estrella de mar brillante"
            },
            {
              "front": "He watched the soft jellyfish float",
              "back": "observó cómo flotaban las suaves medusas."
            },
            {
              "front": "They spotted a fast dolphin swimming",
              "back": "vieron un delfín nadando velozmente"
            },
            {
              "front": "We observed a strong shark swimming",
              "back": "observamos un tiburón nadando con fuerza."
            },
            {
              "front": "She saw the playful seals swimming",
              "back": "ella vio a las focas juguetonas nadando"
            },
            {
              "front": "I heard the singing whale underwater",
              "back": "escuché el canto de la ballena bajo el agua."
            },
            {
              "front": "They touched the colorful coral reefs",
              "back": "tocaron los coloridos arrecifes de coral."
            },
            {
              "front": "He ate a delicious hard clam",
              "back": "comió una deliciosa almeja dura"
            },
            {
              "front": "We cooked a tasty fresh lobster",
              "back": "cocinamos una sabrosa langosta fresca"
            },
            {
              "front": "She caught a small squid quickly",
              "back": "ella atrapó un calamar pequeño rápidamente"
            },
            {
              "front": "I saw a slow turtle swimming",
              "back": "vi una tortuga nadando lentamente"
            },
            {
              "front": "He spotted a long eel hiding",
              "back": "vio una anguila larga escondida"
            },
            {
              "front": "She removed tiny barnacles from boat",
              "back": "ella sacó pequeños percebes del barco"
            },
            {
              "front": "They swam with a graceful manta",
              "back": "nadaban con una elegante manta"
            },
            {
              "front": "I studied the floating plankton closely",
              "back": "estudié de cerca el plancton flotante."
            },
            {
              "front": "He avoided the spiky sea urchins",
              "back": "evitaba los erizos de mar puntiagudos"
            },
            {
              "front": "We caught fresh crayfish for dinner",
              "back": "cogimos cangrejos de río frescos para cenar."
            },
            {
              "front": "She shucked a salty oyster carefully",
              "back": "ella abrió con cuidado una ostra salada"
            },
            {
              "front": "He observed a venomous sea snake",
              "back": "observó una serpiente marina venenosa"
            },
            {
              "front": "They fed the tiny seahorses carefully",
              "back": "alimentaron cuidadosamente a los pequeños caballitos de mar."
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "future",
          "wordcount": 3,
          "phrases": [
            { "front": "Will catch fish", "back": "atrapará peces" },
            { "front": "Will eat shrimp", "back": "comerá camarones" },
            { "front": "Will see crab", "back": "verá cangrejo" },
            { "front": "Will find octopus", "back": "encontrará pulpo" },
            { "front": "Will collect seaweed", "back": "recogerá algas" },
            { "front": "Will spot starfish", "back": "verá estrellas de mar" },
            { "front": "Will watch jellyfish", "back": "observaré medusas" },
            {
              "front": "Will swim with dolphin",
              "back": "nadaré con delfines"
            },
            { "front": "Will observe shark", "back": "observará tiburones" },
            { "front": "Will see seal", "back": "verá foca" },
            { "front": "Will hear whale", "back": "escuchará ballenas" },
            { "front": "Will touch coral", "back": "tocará el coral" },
            { "front": "Will eat clam", "back": "comeré almejas" },
            { "front": "Will cook lobster", "back": "cocinaré langosta" },
            { "front": "Will catch squid", "back": "atrapará calamares" },
            { "front": "Will see turtle", "back": "verá tortuga" },
            { "front": "Will spot eel", "back": "avistará anguilas" },
            { "front": "Will remove barnacle", "back": "eliminará el percebe" },
            { "front": "Will see manta", "back": "verá manta" },
            { "front": "Will find plankton", "back": "encontrará plancton" },
            { "front": "Will spot urchin", "back": "detectará erizos" },
            {
              "front": "Will catch crayfish",
              "back": "atrapará cangrejos de río"
            },
            { "front": "Will eat oyster", "back": "comerá ostras" },
            { "front": "Will see sea snake", "back": "verá serpiente marina" },
            {
              "front": "Will spot seahorse",
              "back": "avistará caballitos de mar"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "future",
          "wordcount": 4,
          "phrases": [
            { "front": "I will catch a fish", "back": "voy a pescar un pez" },
            {
              "front": "She will eat fresh shrimp",
              "back": "ella comerá camarones frescos"
            },
            { "front": "They will see a crab", "back": "verán un cangrejo" },
            {
              "front": "He will find an octopus",
              "back": "encontrará un pulpo"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will collect seaweed tomorrow",
              "back": "mañana recogeremos algas"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will spot a starfish",
              "back": "veré una estrella de mar"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will watch the jellyfish",
              "back": "ella observará las medusas"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will swim with dolphins",
              "back": "nadarán con delfines"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will observe a shark",
              "back": "observaremos un tiburón"
            },
            { "front": "He will see a seal", "back": "verá una foca" },
            { "front": "I will hear a whale", "back": "escucharé una ballena" },
            {
              "front": "They will touch colorful coral",
              "back": "tocarán corales coloridos"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will eat a clam",
              "back": "ella comerá una almeja"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will cook a lobster",
              "back": "voy a cocinar una langosta"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will catch a squid",
              "back": "él atrapará un calamar"
            },
            { "front": "We will see a turtle", "back": "veremos una tortuga" },
            {
              "front": "They will spot a long eel",
              "back": "verán una anguila larga"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will remove a barnacle",
              "back": "voy a quitar un percebe"
            },
            { "front": "She will see a manta", "back": "ella verá una manta" },
            {
              "front": "They will find floating plankton",
              "back": "encontrarán plancton flotante"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will spot a spiky urchin",
              "back": "voy a ver un erizo puntiagudo"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will catch fresh crayfish",
              "back": "cogeremos cangrejos de río frescos"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will eat a fresh oyster",
              "back": "comerá una ostra fresca"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will see a sea snake",
              "back": "ella verá una serpiente marina"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will spot a tiny seahorse",
              "back": "veré un pequeño caballito de mar"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "future",
          "wordcount": 5,
          "phrases": [
            { "front": "I will catch a fish", "back": "voy a pescar un pez" },
            {
              "front": "She will eat fresh shrimp",
              "back": "ella comerá camarones frescos"
            },
            { "front": "They will see a crab", "back": "verán un cangrejo" },
            {
              "front": "He will find an octopus",
              "back": "encontrará un pulpo"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will collect seaweed tomorrow",
              "back": "mañana recogeremos algas"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will spot a starfish",
              "back": "veré una estrella de mar"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will watch jellyfish float",
              "back": "ella observará las medusas flotar"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will swim with dolphins",
              "back": "nadarán con delfines"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will observe a shark",
              "back": "observaremos un tiburón"
            },
            { "front": "He will see a seal", "back": "verá una foca" },
            { "front": "I will hear a whale", "back": "escucharé una ballena" },
            {
              "front": "They will touch colorful coral",
              "back": "tocarán corales coloridos"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will eat a clam",
              "back": "ella comerá una almeja"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will cook a lobster",
              "back": "voy a cocinar una langosta"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will catch a squid",
              "back": "él atrapará un calamar"
            },
            { "front": "We will see a turtle", "back": "veremos una tortuga" },
            { "front": "They will spot an eel", "back": "verán una anguila" },
            {
              "front": "I will remove a barnacle",
              "back": "voy a quitar un percebe"
            },
            { "front": "She will see a manta", "back": "ella verá una manta" },
            {
              "front": "We will find plankton in water",
              "back": "encontraremos plancton en el agua"
            },
            { "front": "He will spot a urchin", "back": "él verá un erizo" },
            {
              "front": "We will catch a crayfish",
              "back": "cogeremos un cangrejo de río"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will eat an oyster",
              "back": "ella comerá una ostra"
            },
            { "front": "He will see a snake", "back": "verá una serpiente" },
            {
              "front": "They will spot a seahorse",
              "back": "verán un caballito de mar"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "tense": "future",
          "wordcount": 6,
          "phrases": [
            {
              "front": "I will catch the big fish",
              "back": "atraparé el pez grande"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will eat the fresh shrimp",
              "back": "ella comerá los camarones frescos"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will see the red crab",
              "back": "verán el cangrejo rojo"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will find the smart octopus",
              "back": "encontrará al pulpo inteligente"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will collect the green seaweed",
              "back": "recogeremos las algas verdes"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will spot the bright starfish",
              "back": "veré la estrella de mar brillante"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will watch the soft jellyfish",
              "back": "él observará las medusas suaves."
            },
            {
              "front": "They will swim with the dolphin",
              "back": "nadarán con el delfín"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will observe the strong shark",
              "back": "observaremos al fuerte tiburón"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will see the playful seal",
              "back": "ella verá la foca juguetona"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will hear the singing whale",
              "back": "escucharé el canto de la ballena"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will touch the colorful coral",
              "back": "tocarán el coral colorido"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will eat the hard clam",
              "back": "él comerá la almeja dura"
            },
            {
              "front": "We will cook the tasty lobster",
              "back": "cocinaremos la sabrosa langosta"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will catch the small squid",
              "back": "ella atrapará el calamar pequeño"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will see the slow turtle",
              "back": "veré la tortuga lenta"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will spot the long eel",
              "back": "él avistará la anguila larga"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will remove the tiny barnacle",
              "back": "ella quitará el pequeño percebe"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will swim with the graceful manta",
              "back": "nadarán con la graciosa manta"
            },
            {
              "front": "I will study the floating plankton",
              "back": "estudiaré el plancton flotante."
            },
            {
              "front": "He will avoid the spiky urchins",
              "back": "evitará a los erizos puntiagudos."
            },
            {
              "front": "We will catch the fresh crayfish",
              "back": "cogeremos los cangrejos de río frescos"
            },
            {
              "front": "She will shuck the salty oyster",
              "back": "ella abrirá la ostra salada"
            },
            {
              "front": "He will observe the venomous snake",
              "back": "observará la serpiente venenosa"
            },
            {
              "front": "They will feed the tiny seahorses",
              "back": "alimentarán a los pequeños caballitos de mar."
            }
          ]
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}
